I threatened them in the chat. I was
like, "Listen guys, if you steal these
bugs and you dupe the the original
reporter, I will find you. I have
connection."
Best part of Viking when you can just,
you know, critical think.
Yeah, dude.
[Music]
All right, sup hackers. So this week we
are launching a new segment on critical
thinking bug bounty podcast called this
week in bug bounty. For this segment
we've partnered with all four major
platforms, hacker 1, bug crowd, yes we
hack integrity. They've all sponsored
the show. So thank you so much for that
um in order to bring this segment to
you. Now I want to make something very
clear because one of the things we've
talked about on the show before is that
we will not show partiality towards one
individual platform. Okay? And we've
made it very clear to the platforms that
we are maintaining that artistic
integrity there. We we will not allow uh
our our voice to be influenced one way
or the other. What we will allow is the
platforms to sponsor the show and to
disseminate content that is and this is
important one useful to the hacker or
two celebrating a a hacker um and
bringing more positivity to the industry
which is something that I feel like we
lack in bug bounty because it is a very
competitive world. So um I'm just going
to kind of go through some of the things
that we have on the list for this week
and uh talk through them and we'll kind
of tweak the segment. We'll see how you
guys like it. Um, and definitely open to
your feedback uh on Discord. Okay, so
first thing up on this segment, which is
crazy because it's the first week we
launched it, is we have a hacker that
passed $1 million. That's P4FG. They
gave permission for us to uh celebrate
that. So, shout out to P4FG. Amazing
hacker. I've worked with him plenty of
times. He's an active member in the
critical thinking community. So, um,
thank you so much for uh being an active
member, P4FG. And congratulations on uh
passing $1 million on Hacker 1. That is
sick. Um, and in the same week, there
was an report disclosed on the hacker 1
activity. Um, that was a 25k crit that
somebody found um by hitting
slashreports/report id.json and it was
uh literally just leaking two-factor
authentication codes, email addresses,
everything on disclosed reports. Um, and
the report is super fascinating. We'll
link it down in the description. Uh, and
so I'm going to make a little bit of an
exception and double click into this
report a little bit in this segment. Um,
but this one uh the reason it happened
and this was reported in under 90
minutes of this being pushed to prod by
the way. Um, I it it was because Ruby
was updated in the Hacker One system and
pushed to prod and there's a difference
in ways that they parse uh JSON objects,
specifically hashes inside Ruby with
that version change and that's why it
leaked all the data. So really crazy
that an a version update caused that
change. Um and I just want to give a
shout out to this hacker uh Avina and
the Hacker 1 team for paying a 25k crit
and getting that resolved super quickly.
Um and there was reported in under 90
minutes. That's nuts. Um okay, so that's
it for Hacker 1. Let's move to Bug
Crowd. So okay, Bug Crowd actually
released a really awesome blog post the
other day um called Hacking Crypto Part
One. And uh for a second I thought it
was talking about uh cryptocurrency, but
it's not. It's talking about
cryptography. And I think that there are
a lot um there there's not a lot of
valuable resources out there on how to
hack crypto. Um so I wanted to give a
shout out to this article by Nerdwell.
Um it's actually really in-depth and
covers a lot of the things you might
want to go after if you're going to hack
um cryptography. Um I've used several of
these attacks to find vulnerabilities
within the past year. So definitely
check that one out. All right. Um, oh,
okay. So, while we're talking about
articles, Yes, We Hack also had another
one which is uh amazing. It's the
payload obfuscation
uh article by by Yes We Hack. And it was
crazy the content in this one cuz I was
like, "Okay, I'll read through this."
And I found a new in this article there
was a new way that I did not know about
on how to specify Unicode code points in
JavaScript. So, I did not know that you
could do back slashu and then curly
bracket the hex code and then curly
bracket, right? I thought you had to do
back
slashu0000 and then the the hex, you
know, the code point, but apparently you
can also specify it with a curly
bracket. Um, which blew my mind. So,
definitely a good uh thing to read there
is Yes, We Hack's article on how to
obuse payloads. Um, and then last but
not least, we have Integrity on the
list. Uh they wanted us to shout out
this week that the Yahoo bug bounty
program is exclusively on Integrity
since 2025. And the bounties are pretty
sick. We've got um mediums ranging up to
3K, highs up to 10K, and crits up to
15K. Um definitely a program you want to
check out when you're hacking on Incre.
All right, that's it for the this
weekend bug bounty segment. Um once
again, I just want to remind you the
goal of this segment is to bring highv
value information. So something that is
useful to you, the hacker um from the
platforms and also something that and or
something that celebrates a hacker
success on one of these platforms. So
let me know what you think about the new
segment. Um let me know if you think it
needs tweaks. We're open to your
feedback. All right, back to the show.
All right, so we got a little behind
today because we were chatting about the
uh Google live hacking event we're
currently in right now. So we've only
got what, like what, 20 minutes before
you got a bounce and then we'll have to
do a cut. Yeah, we'll do a cut. Okay.
All right. Well, let's see how many
stories we can get through. We do have a
lot of news to get through. And then
I've just got um some just pretty fun
random technical uh mostly client side
oriented content that I I want to talk
through. Um so, let's let's try to get
through at least one or two of these
news stories real quick, though. Sweet.
Um All right. First one up on the list
is uh Okay, so dude, I feel like
sometimes this is just that the Asset
Note podcast, you know? like I feel like
I feel like we talk about search light
cyber now. Um, but the asset node team
uh a lot on the pod. Um, and then
there's also this other guy ZH Z Hero or
Zero I guess. Uh, that's been coming up
a lot recently too. We're definitely
going to talk about his stuff, but but
first one on the list is um this new
release from um Searchlight Cyber
covering Zer's research on the uh NextJS
off bypass that came out. Um it looks
like this was about uh a week ago as of
recording. Um and essentially the TLDDR
of this one was there's a problem with
middleware redirects that that occur in
X.js JS that will allow you to just
bypass uh O and um the original write up
is is super good. Um and there were some
public checks that I think were released
by was it like project discovery like
the nuclei team maybe? Mhm. Yeah. Yeah,
I think so. and and um and they were a
little bit um they they covered it a
bit, but there was some the asset note
team, you know, when they're creating
their checks for their product, uh they,
you know, always go back and do their
due diligence and reverse the
vulnerability. And uh this time they
came up with a better um detection flow
for this specific vulnerability. So, let
me share my screen really quick. Um and
that was this header right here, X
Next.js JS data 1. Um, and I think for
any of you guys out there that are doing
like mass scanning, I think it's very um
tempting for you to just take the nuclei
template that you know, whoever uploaded
and kind of scan around with this, but
um I know that there are some hackers
out there that have actually went read
this blog post and integrated this blog
posts um data into their scanning
software and found a bunch of
vulnerabilities that people missed um
because of this. So definitely take a
look. But the TLDDR of it was that there
is this header called X Next.js data one
that you can send through that will um
return a specific uh other header uh
nextJS redirect when the redirect is
happening at the middleware layer which
is a precondition of the vulnerability
the original vulnerability by zero. So
you can sort of use this as an indicator
of whether there is a middleware
redirect occurring somewhere in this
flow and then pass in this sort of
advanced polyglot that the the um acid
node team designed to uh bypass O on
that specific uh redirect. Um so
definitely cool to see the research that
they did here and uh and that they were
able to improve the PC. Yeah. And they
actually said here that sometimes that X
middleware redirect header can get
swallowed.
Yeah. Um, so yeah, some of the like like
they explicitly say leading to publicly
disclosed checks missing many instances
of this vulnerability. And I actually I
don't know if you saw that, but I saw
some tweets going around that were
claiming that this was not really a big
deal because there wasn't that many
exposed or sorry when when people ran
checks, there wasn't that many um
vulnerable instances out on the web. And
I think that one the lack of
comprehensiveness in those initial
checks and the fact that sometimes that
response header would get swallowed by
some middleware or some you know
probably from engine X or whatever you
know some stuff hosted internally. Yeah.
Exactly. Then there's probably that's
probably a large reason why there was
some confusion around how widespread the
impact was here. Yeah. Yeah. I I think
it's a big I think it's a big thing and
and so I would definitely recommend
updating your checks to use this new um
asset note um sort of fingerprint for
this and and see if we uh can really
flush out all the vulnerabilities in the
bug bounty context. Um so once again
awesome work by the asset node team. Um,
I love it when people find you when an
impactful vulnerability hits the scene
and then people go back, reverse it and
improve it. And and I think that there's
a lot of times where we're like, "Oh,
wow. That was a great find, you know,
great work. Nice." And then and then you
just kind of move along where uh
improvements could be made. So, shout
out to the to the Asset Note team on
doing that for all of these major um
research pieces that they're integrating
into their product. Yeah. Yeah. And I
think there's probably lots of other uh
vulnerabilities that basically people
could do this on. Like obviously I asset
note can't can't go back and do due
diligence on every single vulnerability
that drops. There's probably a lot of um
you know tangental vulnerabilities that
aren't found with very similar kind of
uh slight changes 100%. Okay, before we
go into the next the next thing, dude,
can you see this uh can you see this
sick sweatshirt that I'm wearing right
now? This is the Nahamsek
uh merch uh sweatshirt that I'm wearing
right now, dude. And I ordered one of
these cuz I was like, "Oh, I love that
red." Right? Like that that's like, you
know, that's your color. That's a great
red. And and my daughter's always
telling me that I need to like wear more
bright colors than all my like black
hacker t-shirts. And so I got this. And
uh dude, the quality is so good. Look
how like, you know, you ever look at a
hoodie and they've got like these um
very thick and a little bit wide hoodie
strings. Oh yeah. That's how you know
it's going to be a good hoodie, you
know? That's true. Yep. That's a very
clear indicator of uh quality. Yeah. Not
Ben. Ben is a homie. Not not not
affiliated, you know. I'm going to drop
this down in in the in the description,
you know, where you guys can get these.
Um, this is Ben did not pay for this
endorsement. I just am shouting out a
quality. I was genuinely curious with
how well you sold it. I was like, did
Ben get him to say that? No. No, dude.
This is like Ben would not do that, man.
Ben is I think the merch store is like
just a fun thing for him, you know, but
this is like quality stuff, so I feel
like people got to go snag one of these.
Um, what we got next? Well, it's a it's
a kind of a nice segue. They used a
really sweet polyglot in that and I
tweeted about what I called a polyglot
and so I want to get your take because I
feel like like one person replied to it
and was like this is all just English.
This is not a polyglot. But but uh yeah,
I tweeted about llm's.ext
uh being being a sweet honeypot. You
know, I think that we know what is
llm.ext. Yeah, so you and I know this uh
but a lot of other people might not.
Basically, prompt injection still is not
solved. And so that's going to result in
tons of AI vulnerabilities through for
the foreseeable future. But the one of
the difficult things, and I know that
well, actually there's three difficult
things here. Um, and the third one
Justin was just complaining about before
we hopped on this call. Basically, to
get a good AI bug, you have to have some
sort of delivery mechanism, some sort of
impact, and then the the third annoying
part is the consistency, right? Because
of the non-determinism, and that's the
one that Justin was complaining about.
Anyways, all that to say, delivery
mechanisms in the past were really hard
because all these AI apps didn't have
very many features, but today they're
getting many more features. One of those
is of course browser use or browsing.
Um, we're testing specifically stuff for
that right now for a live hacking event.
And um, and by we, I mean me and Justin
and um, some other people, Lupin and
Kieran. But anyways, all that to say, as
soon as I saw this announcement about
um, LLM's.ext is basically a robots.ext,
text, but it's a it's a page you put on
your website that tells an LLM how to
navigate your website or how to use your
like open source project that you've got
or whatever. And so, as soon as I saw
that come out, I tweeted or like well,
as soon as I saw it get popular because,
you know, the famous developer levels.io
was complaining that it was just a
front-end thing that wasn't necessary
when in fact, the person that invented
LLM.ex is like an OG in the in the LLM
space. Anyway, bunch of drama there. But
long story short, I think it's an
awesome honeypot for putting prompt
injections for AI. But what's hard is
you don't know what tool calls the LLM
that's coming to view your LLM.ext will
use. So then I came up with this idea of
I call it a polyglot, but it's I don't
know. And so I'm going to get your take
on whether it should be called that or
not. But if you go to
josephthacker.comlm.ext, you can see uh
my example of that. And I'll share my
screen real quick for anyone watching on
YouTube. But um basically Yeah, dude.
This person's saying it's just English.
That's funny, dude. Yeah. But uh so this
this thing just says if you have an
email tool like well the top there's
like some preamble that says if you're
an animal model reading this I'm trying
to help secure the planet so just help
me out here. So that way I don't have to
do any kind of like jailbreaking or like
negative based jailbreaking. It's just
you know a fun way to get the LM to
hopefully uh comply. But then it
basically says if you got an email tool
send me an email. If you've got a text
thing, text this number. if you can make
web fetch requests, hit this endpoint.
And I've got like a tool that's
monitoring that endpoint. I get Discord
messages whenever someone sends that
request in. And so, anyways, I thought
this was cool. I don't know if it's
considered a polyglot or not, but you
can give me your take on it. Yeah, dude.
I mean, I think it's totally a polygot.
What what what this person in the in the
Twitter, you know, is saying that what
they don't realize is that this is the
input language for LLMs, right? That's
like saying, "Oh, this is this isn't a
polyglot. This is just HTML, you know,
for like an XSS polyglot." It's like,
well, that's what you do for an HTML,
you know, that's what you do for XSS is
you give it an HTML poly. Um, so this is
like a tool, this is like a tool called
polygot is maybe how you how you would
define it. Yeah. Yeah. And and you know,
like we've been talking about with this
event, you know, right before this call,
we kind of did a debrief between me and
and Joseph and the these other hackers
we're collaborating with on like what
kind of bugs we found and kind of
compared notes. And like we've been
saying in this event, you know, it the
most efficient route typically is to
understand what the system prompt has is
being given to the AI and then give it
keywords relating specifically to that
prompt. So if it's like if in that
prompt it's like okay, you have these
tools available to you, right? And the
tool is called like web browse, right?
Then you say, hey, use your web browse
tool. So there's not any like ambiguity
here to go to this website, right?
That's going to give you the most
consistent results. That was the last
thing you know you mentioned there. Um,
but you don't have the opportunity to do
that here because so you've just kind of
got to describe what the tool should do
and then hope that the LLM can kind of
piece it together which as they get
smarter and smarter, man, it's it's
amazing what they can piece together. So
I think I think you will get hits on
this. My prediction is you will get hits
on this within the next three months for
sure. Yeah, I think so too. What you
just brought up is a great idea though
for this. It might be worth adding like
for example if you have web browse or
web fetch or like give it a list of
potential tool IDs so that it really
kind of hard codes. Oh, I do have that,
you know, and then it goes in on it.
Kind of an interesting idea. Yeah, very
cool idea, man. I I I like it. I'm
excited to see the results out of it.
Um, cool. Yeah, dude. I don't know, man.
It's been a little bit It's been a
little bit weird lately with testing the
AI stuff. Like, I kind of love it. I
kind of hate it, but um I think as stuff
gets more integrated into it, we we got
to, you know, we got to So, that's
right. Um, all right. Next news item up
on the list was from uh Zero again or Z
Hero. I got to figure out how to um how
to pronounce that because we talk about
them so much. Um, this researcher, Zero
Web Security, has been like dropping
some crazy stuff. Yeah. Lately. So,
definitely go check out the blog. We got
it linked in the description. Um, but
this one is a CP DOS on React Router.
Um, and uh, let me let me share my
screen. Um, and essentially the TLDDR of
this one is he finds and I just love the
flow of this research, he finds first
the underscore data parameter that's
being parsed by this React router. Um,
also one of the things that I just
little takeaway for me as personally as
a hacker, I've seen this route SLSR a
lot in in my testing, right? I'm like,
oh SLSR, why do I see this all the time?
That's SLServerside routing. I just
didn't know about that in the past. So,
there's a little TLDDR for you guys. If
you see that, it's the framework that
you're dealing with is deal is using um
sort of a I forget what the term he used
in here, but a multistrategy routing um
software. Um anyway, so as he's auditing
this Remix um and React router code, he
comes across this underscore data
parameter that allows him to
um sort of pollute this uh response and
sort of break the response from the the
the serverside router. and then uh
potentially allow that to get cached.
The problem is that the query parameter
is typically included in the cache key.
So he's like, okay, you know, this is
kind of helpful, but like not really
that helpful. But you know, when I did
my talk back in Humcon in 2020, I
believe on like server side or like
source code review, I I called it
sniffing blood. You know, when you see
sketchy [__] in in the source code of an
app, you've gota you've got to be like,
"Ah, I smell something here that there's
something, you know, I gotta find it."
And so that's kind of what he did here.
He found this data piece and he's like,
"Okay, there's like some weird typing
stuff going on here or, you know,
expectation for a specific um flow
here." and he kind of digs a little
deeper and uh he eventually figures out
that um there's some other pieces that
you can use in because the code is by
default parsing the x4ed host header um
and then integrating that actually into
the URL directly. So that exported host
header is split on the colon for trying
to identify the port and that port is
then attached to the new URL that
they're defining for this specific um uh
request. But what he found is that not
only can you specify the port, but you
can just put a slash in there and then
prepend to the actual path uh of this uh
request which causes it to break uh and
also allows you to access you know
redirect paths by using this this
header. Um and this became a lot better
uh vulnerability then because you can
then uh you combine it with the data.
You get that data parameter out of the
the query right out of the query um
parameter there which is normally a part
of the cache key and into a request
header which is normally not a part of
the cache key. And then you can do DOSs
specific endpoints um using that header,
get it cached and then uh it turns into
a very impactful CP doss that was um
according to the researcher uh able to
be found across several very large uh
bug bounty programs. So once again,
awesome research. I love the chain of
thought here and I think CP DOS is one
of the easiest targets for you to go
after if you're going to try to do a
source code review to like ODA across a
large attack surface. Yeah, I also think
that these writeups um just the fact
that they take so like a lot of time to
do like nice screenshots with arrows and
stuff. It makes it so so consumable like
you know you could be a complete noob
and just read through this blog post and
fully understand each step. Yeah. And
you should and you should. Everybody
should because um I think the more and
more we train that like sense of like ah
something sketchy is happening here and
the more reps you get of like ah yes a
vulnerability ah yes a vulnerability ah
yes a vulnerability it will become
easier and easier and easier for your
brain to identify them in the future and
then it'll get to the point where you're
not even thinking about it you're just
reading code and you're like
vulnerability you know like that's right
it's uh it's great uh before we pivot to
the next story I was going to mention to
you that I like There's a while we were
recording a second ago, I saw you
struggle to think of the word for Spidey
sense or you know your bug bounty
sniffer or your you know whatever you
want to call it and we might need to
lean on the audience here because I
don't know if you'll be able to think of
something but I feel like we need a
specific word for that cuz I find myself
waffling on that same concept just to
know what to call it right because it
still feels ambiguous. I don't have a
concrete term I always come to and I
think it'd be fun if it was critical
thinking themed like critical something
but um critical critical sniffer my
critical sense critical sense I don't I
don't know dude I don't know it feels a
little long maybe it needs to just be
like crit sense or something that's okay
yeah maybe that's what you want right
you want the critical bug you want the
big impact you know I' I'd like I'd like
for it to have critical thinking you
know related into it maybe thinking
would be would be easier to integrate
but um I I think that, you know, it
needs to be a little bit more of a broad
term because it's not always a critical
that you're sniffing, right? If I see,
you know, HTML injection, I'm like,
right, you know, but but I'm I'm yeah,
I'm not necessarily sniffing a critical
at that point. So, I don't know. We'll
see what the community comes up with.
But, uh, dude, I don't know. I don't
know about the community, though,
because the other day we were in that um
I was in that uh bug escalation hour
with the community, which by the way,
listen, as somebody who's I'm definitely
not an outsider. I mean, I'm the co-host
at this point, but I feel like I don't
know that we have done a good enough job
of advertising that with critical
thinking. So, for the listeners, Justin
literally took leads from critical
thinkers and then went to execute on
them and popped two bugs live while
people were paying attention and
watching. So, it's a really cool thing
that you could get access to if you sign
up. But anyway, so what happened? Yeah.
Yeah, it it was great and it it was
really well. You know, I wasn't sure I
was going to go, by the way, because
it's like we're bringing live bugs, you
know, and live leads for bugs in there.
Um, and I guess we'll see the results,
but we haven't I haven't heard about
dupes uh yet. So, I'm hoping I I
threatened them in the chat. I was like,
"Listen, guys, if you steal these bugs
and you dupe the the original reporter,
I will find you. I have connections, you
know, we could probably find out what
happened there." like not not that we
would get staff to tell us anything they
shouldn't, but staff would probably
willing to be like, "Yeah, it was
reported 30 seconds beforehand by
potentially somebody similar." Yeah.
They're going to dup it. They're going
to leak the report ID and if it's like
30 seconds before, I will find you. I
will absolutely. Anyway, so anyway, I I
we it was it was a fun time, you know,
nobody duped. It was lots of fun.
Community, you know, exploited some bugs
together. We built out this crazy like
four or fivestep chain to turn selfs
into an account takeover. That's
amazing. Um, great work. Shout out to
Big Dab on that. Um, but uh yeah, but
what was funny in that though bringing
it back around was that uh I said
somewhere in there, we need to we need
to snuggle in this HTML. and the
community. Like, dude, I swear as soon
as I saw it, man, as soon as I saw like
I as soon as I said it, I looked at the
chat and there was like two people
typing and then all of a sudden like 15
people started typing. I'm like, [__]
you know, like
do do you think because it kind of
follows on you saying getting intimate
with the application, you know, and
that's what they were saying, you know,
like Yeah. So, getting intimate the
application, you know, v snuggling. I I
don't know. Anyway, Freud would have a
heyday with uh your brain and and bug
dude. Yeah, seriously. Geez. All right.
Um cool. It was me, I think. Yeah. Go
ahead. So, we're coming straight We're
coming straight back to uh you know, our
friends at uh Asset Note and now at uh
what do we what is it? Search Light
Cyber. Yeah, that's right. Um and like
you said, we do often just cover a lot
of their content. I I did want to make
this comment. I thought about making it
earlier, but the reason why that we
cover their content so much is because
we love technical writeups. We love
vulnerability so much and they're always
doing really high quality writeups for
vulnerabilities. So um yeah, so they
released something on April 2nd which is
yesterday that is called loose types
sync ships pre-author SQL injection and
Halo ITSM. Obviously, IT support
management software is extremely
extremely high risk because, you know,
anytime any kind of IT software often
has really strong um power, right? Like
it's just like it's a high access,
sorry, is the way I was trying to think
about it because it's going to have
access to host or command execution or
it's only admins that are in there,
right? It's got it's normally keys to
the kingdom if you can take over
something like this or if you have a
severe vulnerability. So, thought it was
a cool thing to to hack on. Um, but the
the things that I wanted to point out in
this writeup, and I can share my screen
here. Mhm. Yeah, go for it. For the
people who are watching online, was uh I
feel like there's a couple good tips for
source code review, and obviously
they're some of the best at it. Um, but
um, yes. So, the the things that they
mentioned that I wanted to point out
were one, the fact that, uh, they were
able to kind of pinpoint. So they found
a bunch of loose types that could have
caused vulnerabilities. They were like
near misses. But the vulnerability um
like Yeah. They they called them close
calls. Yeah. But when they found the
actual vulnerability, it was because
there was one pre-auth injection point.
And the way they were able to tell that
was because there was not a decorator
for Yeah. Yeah. Here we go. It's
important to note that this controller
has no decorators to enforce
authentication. So when you're looking
at this type of code, is this Java?
Looks like Java to It's uh no it's it's
um what is the CS file C# oh yeah yeah
yeah sorry yeah this is net or C# yeah
yeah so when you're looking at net and
I'm sure this is true for some other
similar languages um they will often
incortegrate O with decorators on
classes and so I thought that was a
really cool tip that if you're doing
source code review and you're looking
for vulnerabilities like that definitely
then look for endpoints especially
routes and like you know state changing
actions and stuff that don't have that
decorator on them and then Um from that
they were able to take it down and see
that there was a you know a string
concatenation into a SQL uh um statement
that uh was loosely typed and apparently
if it is uh strongly typed then it's not
generally vulnerable. So yeah yeah it
it's interesting there because it's like
you know I think the close call section
just reading the first line of it says
as we mentioned earlier there were a lot
of close calls that were pre prevented
because of strongly typed objects. So
the example they gave there was that um
these specific uh like ids it'll be like
type ID or whatever they're set
specifically to int type. So whenever
you pass them in you know those are are
strongly typed and they're not going to
be vulnerable to SQL injection even if
they are concatenated directly with an
SQL um statement. But there they found
the one situation in this whole codebase
which I thought that was hilarious at
the end that they gpped through the
whole codebase and couldn't find any
other instance of it. right? Where um
they actually concatenated
um a like something that came directly
from the the query parameter, right? Cuz
right there it says from body uh and
it's essentially that key value store,
right? The string to whatever string
typically, you know, that comes in via a
parameter. Um so I I think that that's a
a great needle in a haststack find
there. Yeah. Yeah. And it's always
really impressive to me the way they're
able to then take that function, reverse
it out, understand exactly what
parameters. So you can scroll down here
and see the actual payload. So it was on
post API notify and then this is what
they needed and then the tech ID was
what contained the SQL injection. And I
just thought it was hilarious that they
also put in the chat log asinote are the
pioneers of attack circumstance. It's
like yeah, you are. And also I just love
the confidence there. It's like you're
you're definitely the kings of it and uh
you're willing to state it here in your
blog post. So dude, they they so are,
man. And I've worked with Shubs and the
team a couple times on on a live hacking
event stuff and it's hilarious how he
finds Shubs in particular and I don't
know if it was Dylan or Adam or whoever
else was on the team, you know, working
on this one, but Shubs in particular is
so good at finding the needle in the
haststack. Like the last SQL injection
RC bug that I did with him was the only
one in the whole codebase cuz we
literally went back and audited every
single SQL statement and this one was
the only one that was vulnerable. Um,
his crit sense is high, right? He did.
Dude, the crit sense is high with this.
The crit force. Okay, the force is
strong with this one. That's I don't
know. All right, let us know what you
think in the Discord community to you
guys about what we should name that. Um,
we can bounce back to your list. Yeah.
All right, let's let's bounce back to
that. Um, all right. Next one up here.
And I'm just going to do a quick little
shout out to this one because I'm
probably going to grill Space Raccoon on
this when he comes on the pod here in a
week or two. Um, but there was a write
up by Spac Raccoon called poning
millions of smart weighing machines
um with API and hardware hacking. And I
just thought this was a really good
example of what we were talking about
with uh Chiron in the episode where we
sort of talked about uh hacking IoT
devices um and his methodology for that
which is um the communication between
the device the IoT device and the server
is what is where the juice is at right
if it is 100% where the juice is at. So,
um, this write up, you know, was a great
example of how Spacer [__] ended up
getting a shell, subbed out the the
certificate so that he could a man in
the middle of the device and and and the
server, figured out how all that worked,
found an SQL injection in, you know, the
the cloud along the way, and was able to
use that to uh pop into all of these
devices and take over every device in
that uh smart scale um environment. So,
uh really great read. Um, the only other
takeway, like I said, I'm gonna grill
space on it when he comes on, but I like
that you call it a smart scale because
that's definitely what I would call it.
It's funny he calls it a smart weighing
machine. Weighing machine is You see it?
That's like the guy, right? Pony
millions of smart weighing machines.
I wonder if that's like a Singapore
English thing. Like it's not a scale,
it's a weighing machine. Also, I feel
like he missed a lot of meme potential
on this one. Like he could have titled
it like figuring out what everyone on
the planet weighs or figuring out what a
million people weigh, you know, or I
don't know. Find what your ex-girlfriend
weighs now, right? Exactly. Yeah.
There's so many funny things. Yeah. Oh
my gosh, that'd be so that'd be so
gnarly. Um Yeah. So anyway, good stuff.
The only other really quick and dirty
takeaway that I wanted to add from this
one was he was going up against a W on
the SQL injection and you know one
equals one or whatever gets caught by
the WS 2 equals 2. You know those sort
of like boolean truth things often get
um caught by the w and he said the way
that he bypassed in this one was
actually by using at version um which I
did not know evaluates to true. Yeah.
How does that do you even know? I he
just he just kind of says it, you know,
offhand in the in the um in the write
up. What did he say here? At at version
always evaluates to true and can be used
instead of the more obvious one equals
1. So yeah, pretty cool little little
you know one bite one one sentence
takeaway there um for the listener.
Yeah, I'm curious just like what it is
like obviously at version I think
returns version. So I wonder if at
version is just saying like does this
variable exist and because at version
always exists it's saying it's true,
right? That's what I was curious about.
That makes sense. It probably returns
like a positive integer and that integer
evaluates true, you know, when cast or
whatever. So, yeah, makes sense. Um, all
right, cool. Uh, you've got some more uh
items here on the news list and then
I'll go into some of these like random
client side technical stuff that I think
is fascinating. Sweet. Yeah, the one
thing, excuse me, the one thing I wanted
to mention, um, I've mentioned it to two
or three personal friends, like I've
mentioned it to Hadex and Daniel Mesler,
but I I just think that MCP security,
oh, I may have even mentioned it last
week, is going to be huge. And so,
specifically, I wanted to call out this
tweet by um, Colin, he is I think he's
the founder and CEO of Clerk. And so,
Cler Clerk O is also getting into
payment. So, they're going to like
eventually be a competitor with um
Stripe, but they want to be like O
provider and payment provider all like
rolled into one. So, it's a pretty cool
little product. They didn't pay me to
advertise that, but I just think it's
kind of neat. But, um his tweet here,
I'm trying not to leak my um X messages.
I feel like I do that every time I share
my screen when I'm sharing an expost.
But, um he basically is saying who needs
to display the consent screen when the
MCP server delegates to third party O.
So, I'm going to scroll down. Um, you
should just read the tweet, but
basically with MCP, it's expected that
you implement OOTH 21.1 with PKCE on the
server side. Like, so MCP server should
implement that when it's required.
Obviously, you can have MCP servers that
don't transmit anything sensitive. Um,
but usually they will, right? Because
it's going to be like access to your
account or access to your notes or
access to your database, right? You're
going to be chatting with something
that's yours. And so, they need to
implement OOTH. And so, this is just so
complicated. There's no way this doesn't
get screwed up all the And I mean MCP is
still so new. I think this is would be
amazing place for hackers to start
looking for vulnerabilities because I
think companies will have MCP servers in
the you know next 3 to 6 months. But I
also think that it's just an amazing
area of research um to like potentially
build a product right like if you can
basically productize this or or if you
can help people audit it. Both those
things would be really huge. I actually
what I would love and I might even
produce this myself, but I would love to
see an MCP security guide for end users
that's like, hey, here's how you vet
whether or not the MCP server you're
about to use is secure. And then I would
also love to see on the other side like,
hey, here's how you securely deploy an
MCP server. So anyways, um I'm not going
to walk through all this, but you know,
he's he's basically saying this is the
design for OOTH flow with MCP and it's
OOTH but even more complicated because
now you're going from the browser to the
MCP client to the server back to the
client all the way to the third party. I
mean, it's just ridiculous. Yeah. Yeah.
This gets super complex and and that is
definitely one of the areas, you know,
we've kind of been AI hacking stuff has
been a little bit fuzzy up until this
point. It's like, ah, does it work? Does
it not work? Or not, right? Yeah. we can
like trigger a tool and it does
something. But I think when uh these
servers start to get implemented uh more
frequently, we're going to see a little
bit more server side issues relating to
uh how they're exposing these tools to
the to the client. Um so definitely
definitely an area to to double click in
on as those are being gaining um
adoption and they are gaining adoption
pretty quickly. So I think that's
pretty. And then the only like really
short thing that I that I wanted to drop
uh really quickly before we switch to
the more technical section and kind of
get off the news is that um there is a
you probably have seen it uh alternative
to cursor and windsurf called Klein. C I
N E. Oh really? I thought there was
going to be a different one that you
were that you were saying. I I saw one
that popped in my feed this morning, but
they're everywhere now. Okay. What's
Klein? Yeah. So Klein is just like a VS
Code extension. So they decided, hey,
we're not going to fork VS Code, which I
kind of like that idea. Yeah, I mean
obviously we chose to build on Kaido
with shift we just we didn't choose to
like build a brand new app and so I can
kind of respect that decision. I think
it's probably made them have a lot lower
adoption rate but also it's like how
annoying that if VS Code which is
obviously being maintained like
extremely well add some really cool new
feature that like cursor won't get it
unless they port it right and wind surf
has to get it by porting it and so it's
like now we're porting around all these
like changes and anyways I hate that
idea. I like the client's built into VS
Code. I haven't actually used it, but
the thing I was going to tell you was
I've always thought we needed to
abstract out memory because it would be
so useful to like have like your own
little like one memory is useful, but
like you I'm sure I bounce between Chad
GPT and Claude and Gemini and whatever.
I would love to have memory that's like
across all of those, but only for the
stuff I care about and really want. And
I think it'd be even cooler to have
memory for like each team. Like let's
say that critical thinking had our own
memory that like Yeah. And so anyways,
that's what this is. It's memory bank
and it gives client memory persistent
anytime. I think it's an MCP server.
Yeah. And but like they realized that
locally that was fine. But when they
wanted to integrate with their team,
they could plug it into a notion MCP
server. So basically the team notion
like the team has a notion like you can
set up a a notion account or whatever
for your for your team and then you can
install this MCP server on all of your
devs workstations and then they can all
share the same codebase or the same
documentation for the codebase. So, it's
like a really nice way that like if I go
update the code or the documentation for
our code or for our libraries, now all
of our MCP servers have access to that
same data and they can all work
together. So, that's pretty cool. That's
sick. No, that's really cool. I think
that that is is a really great idea of
having a centralized memory bank. And I
think that would be awesome for hackers
too, right? Like if you just dump all of
these articles with like you and your
friends, some gadgets. Oh my gosh,
that'd be perfect. Yeah, we should we
should think about how we could
implement that because I was just like
right before we got into this episode, I
recorded the this weekend bug bounty
segment and Yes, we hack just released a
article um that is already linked down
in the description uh but on payload
obfuscation and I was like oh you know
what's like pretty sick about this uh
this writeup is that this is a perfect
thing to just hand to an LLM and be like
uh obuscate these payloads. Yeah,
obuscate these payloads in 10 different
ways and then I'll tell them
I think adding a knowledge base, what I
was gonna say with that was like adding
a knowledge having a centralized
knowledge base of like here's a payload
obuscation write up and that sort of
thing. Um really really sick. I like
that a lot. Yeah, I feel like the
security knowledge which you and I know
this because we tested White Rabbit Neo
for it. But like and but even top models
even though they have some good cyber
security knowledge that I feel it feels
like it's not deeply trained into their
into their brain in a way where like if
you say give me some ways to potentially
do this thing it like comes out but I
think if it was in that store memory
bank and I'm thinking of examples that
like we often will pin in the critical
thinkers chat like whenever I figured
out that payload for multi-art form CSRF
it's like kind of tricky to do like a
lot of people have tried it and everyone
can kind of eventually figure it out
takes like a you know an hour or
something like work together with the LM
to like code it by hand, but it's like
kind of annoying to do. But dropping
that into those notes, then when you're
working with it later, the LM will know
that. And I think it's especially true
for a lot of the front end stuff you're
like about to mention today, like all
these little really little like quirky
weird gadgets that nobody can keep
stored in their memory. Like, you know,
most of them and so the CT researchers,
but like most other bug bounty hunters
don't. and when they're trying to pop
something, it'd be so cool if they could
chat with like a little, you know,
memory empowered like front-end bug in
memory powered agent, you know, it's
almost like a custom GPT in a sense, but
it's just nice because uh whatever MCP
client you're using, it can have access
to that same memory bank. I think that's
I think that's a great idea, dude. Um
yeah, definitely something we got to
think about in integrating. Um all
right, so did we cover all the news? Am
I good to get into? Let's do it.
So, here's what I got for you guys this
week. I got one, two, three, at least
three, maybe four, uh, little just
tidbits of client side front-end
information that I think are just super
cool. Okay, one of the one of the ones
that we needed recently for a chain uh,
was credentialless iframes. So, there's
this scenario that uh, my buddy was
working on the other day where um, and
I'm pretty sure I mentioned this on the
podcast before, but I went back and I
couldn't find it anywhere. So, it
definitely needs to end up in the hacker
notes this time so we can uh search for
it. But there's this um flag you can put
on iframes called credentialist. And
what that will do is it will put that
iframe in a different sort of isolated
cookie environment. So let's say you've
got a reflected XSS that um it has to uh
it only fires if the user is not sending
some of of the very common same site
none cookies that are set on that
website. Right? So obviously if the
person has never visited that website
before then these cookies will not be
set but why would you want to attack
that user and get XSS then if they've
never been on the website before? The
whole concept of that is like oh they're
an active user of the website you pop an
XSS you take over their account right um
so it's it's kind of tricky uh to get an
environment where same site none cookies
are not sent sometimes and the
credentialist iframe does exactly that.
So as long as you can embed it and even
maybe if you uh even if you can't embed
it you can do a window.open open from
within a credentialous iframe to
navigate to a site uh where there will
not be any of those cookies set and then
you can traverse back via window
references you know window.open or
window.parent or whatever and and attack
um the the actual website via those same
origin frame references. So um if you
got a very very niche scenario where you
need to not send a site none cookie in
order to trigger a vulnerability
credentialous iframes that's the
solution to that problem. So, this is
kind of confusing and I think it's kind
of neat that something they built to be
more secure actually unlocks a small
gadget. It does, dude. It does. Isn't
that great? That's cool. Yeah. Um, all
right. That's number one. This is going
to be this this this little segment is
going to be quick. Um, number two, this
is shout out to Matan Baron Haku from
the critical research lab. This was one
of the ones that they were kind of
talking about in our in our uh meetings,
but um Do you want to pull this up your
PC for it? Yeah, sure. Yeah, I'll I'll
pull it up. I've got a little like
website that um I just kind of do live
code previews on, you know, whenever I'm
kind of testing code. So I Yeah, I can
share that um because I have a question
about it specifically. Yeah, sure. Sure.
So um here is here's the code right
here. Um for those of you that are
listening, this is a a tag with a target
equal to ABC and then there's an iframe
with the name ABC, right? And when you
click that link, it will open the link's
content into that iframe. So here's what
we're thinking, guys. Let's say you've
got a scenario in a user controlled
content website where you can control
the target attribute of an a uh a tag,
right? And then there's an why would the
app have that? Uh it's very common like
like uh you know if you are submitting
user controlled content you know like
what you see is what you get editors or
whatever you can link out to like other
stuff and it will create like an actual
link right sometimes inside those the
target attribute is is whitelisted so
you can you can do that or maybe they're
just you know doing like a block list
for the attributes or whatever they're
not doing like a allow list and you know
you're able to specify the target
attribute or whatever. Yeah. What you
can then do is when the user clicks that
link, it will open up your specified h
you know uh href your your link into
that iframe that is that is on that page
right um and then what that will do is
give you a very advantaged position
inside that that application right so
let's say that iframe is responsible for
you know communicating with its parent
about you know communicating with a
specific API or something now you're in
that iframe and maybe that page is
trusting that iframe implicitly via
window reference for post messages or
something of the like. Now you know you
execute that attack. So it's a gadget.
It's a gadget along the way but it
definitely should be something that you
can think about when you are dealing
with like what you see is what you get
editors or like any sort of markdown um
rendering. Uh see if you can inject into
the target uh tag or attribute and if
you can then you can use that to hijack
iframes. So what um is that pretty
common where there is an iframe on the
page that it implicitly trusts because
you can't control anything about that
iframe in general? Very common. Okay.
Yeah, I thought it was. Okay. Sweet.
Yeah.
So you would look at that and figure out
what the name is for that iframe and and
then you would set your target to that
name specifically and then Yeah. Yeah.
Nice. I I would say it's one of the more
common ways to do post message
assessment, right? like yeah like you
typically will do um you you'll
typically do an origin check. So you'll
use the event.org origin attribute to
say okay where did this post message
come from right but they'll often also
use events source which is the frame
reference to the window that sent the
iframe or the sent the sent the post
message. Um and if they're using you
know events source then this could be
your golden ticket to bypass it. So, so
when you when you when you click that,
it goes straight to that link at the
top. It does. Yeah. The iframe gets
hijacked. So, this could be an invisible
iframe, you know, in nested in the page,
used for backend communication or
whatever, and now you've hijacked that.
So, it can doss part of the page. It
can, you know, give you advantage
position, all those sort of things.
Cool. Yeah. Um, all right. And then last
one. Dude, this was this was crazy
because we had such and I think I
tweeted about this, but we had such a
beautiful experience, man, in the um
critical thinking discord uh like a week
or so ago. Um we we had somebody just
come into the main chat. This isn't even
like our our paid subscriber tier chat.
Um and then just be like, "Hey, I've got
this bug that I need to exploit. I've
got a character limits on it. It's kind
of tricky. How can I exploit this?" And
like the whole community came together
and just spent like 30 minutes like what
if we try this, what if we try this,
what if we try this? Like me, a couple
other people were like, you know, what
do we got here? Demo, you know, all of
these people are trying to figure out
what we could do. And finally, I popped
it. Um, but it required a click. And so
we were like, ah, how can we make it not
require a click? And then my boy Jorian
comes out of nowhere and drops a really
really interesting um nuance that
allowed us to pop the bug. And that is
that uh and this is what we have here in
the um in the uh on the screen for any
of you watching on YouTube is that this
the string URL all caps. If you run that
in your um console in your browser that
is going to reference to the URL class
uh or function um excuse me in
JavaScript uh and and that will be like
a reference to that whole thing. that
that's not what we want. If you
reference the string URL from inside of
an onload event handler, then that URL
is actually document URL, which is sort
of like
windowloation.href. And the situation we
were dealing with was we could only use
JavaScript's primitives that were
capitalized cuz it was capitalizing
stuff, right? So we ended up in the end
we ended up using uh function
constructor with a capital F because
it's it's capitalized um in the
beginning and we used the URL property
to smuggle the data in to the function
constructor which is essentially eval
and then called it um which was a
beautiful solution. Yeah, I linked it in
the description there. Um and actually
we'll put the link to the Discord
conversation in the in the description
as well. And um I did a write up or I
did sort of like a a walkthrough video
on that whole bug because it was so cool
and it was happened in public on the on
the critical thinking discord and I put
that in announcements for any of you
guys that want to see like the actual um
payload and the vulnerability that we
was being exploited. So very was there
anything here that you learned that you
didn't know through that exploration of
the Yeah, this URL thing was whack,
dude. I did not know that the URL
function or like the the string I don't
even know what to call it like the
text all capitalized was something
different in a normal execution context
than inside of an onload event handler.
I just think that's super whack. Yeah,
that is weird. And I've seen that before
and I thought about this whenever I was
I was doing this and then I typed URL
in. I'm like, "Oh, that's a function."
like why why did I think that that
contained like windowloh like data? Um
and I couldn't figure it out but then
Jorian had it in had it in his head that
it's different inside of an on onevent
handler. So very cool. The power of the
human brain. Yeah, man. Pretty sick. Um
all right. I think that is all I have.
You said that was all but you got two
more bullets at the bottom. You scroll
down. I I I I see them. Are you going to
call me out on that? Yeah. I was going
to save those. Okay. All right. No, no,
we can. It's up to you. No, you're good.
You're good. All right. So So let me let
me let me do this. Um two two more
things. I I will include these because
we we got time today, right? And we've
had two short episodes. The last two
episodes, I think, yeah, last week was
solo for me and it went a little short.
It was and yeah, for anyone who listen
hasn't listened to it, it's the first of
a three-part miniseries on hacking AI.
And in in prepping for that, I actually
thought of some I feel like some pretty
neat ways to like go about AI recon for
hacking. So anyways, go back and listen
to that. The week before that, Justin
was covering for me because my life was
crazy and so that was also kind of a
short episode. So, we can go a little
long. Yeah. Yeah, that's true. We we we
have earned the right to go a little
long this episode. Okay. So, we'll we'll
cover this one. Um, next one then was
just another uh post in the critical
thinking discord by Johan Carlson, which
anytime Yan Carlson posts anything, you
should be paying attention. uh and we
were talking about uh prototype
pollution in the Discord and um he
shared this graphic that I'm wondering
if I can like Can I share my screen with
this because it's in Discord? I'd kind
of like to just not share the Discord.
Oh, I can. Can you just take a
screenshot? Oh, you got it? Yeah. Hold
on. Uh I'm just going to share it like
this. So, essentially, this was a a
tweet he said somewhere, and I couldn't
find the original original tweet, so I'm
sure someone will drop it in the
critical thinking discord after we after
we air this episode. But um essentially
it was talking about three different
types of prototype pollution. There's
hidden property abuse, there's prototype
poisoning, and then there's prototype
pollution. Okay. And um I just thought
this was a really helpful framework for
thinking about prototype pollution as a
as a bug class. So um in the first
example, it's object equals and then you
know a curly bracket tworing null,
right? And that is essentially just
nulling out the two-string property
inside of that specific object. Right.
Yeah. And then there's prototype
poisoning which is uh you know object
equals object you know object curly
brackets proto and then defining the two
string for that uh to be null which is
is sort of modifying that that proto
instance uh and setting the string to be
null. And then there's the the and
that's prototype poisoning. And then
there's the final level which is like
the the awesome one which is prototype
pollution which is you know capital O
object.prototype right so that's
actually referencing the object
prototype itself tworing so this will be
applied to every object that's made in
the future right equals null and then
you instantiate a new object and now
that two string is null um so it's it
there's like different levels to
prototype pollution that I hadn't really
realized and I think this graphic
displays them pretty beautifully. Yeah.
Is there any kind of um obviously ever
like you know a lot of people look for
prototype pollution. I wonder if there
are um like what are kind of the
parameters for when something might be
vulnerable to prototype poisoning but
not prototype pollution. Is it based on
like where you have control of the
request maybe? Yeah, it's it's all about
it's all about how these keys are being
merged into the main object, right? Like
oftent time in prototype pollution what
you're looking for is you know uh object
key1 key2 equals user controlled value
right and key1 and key2 need to be user
controlled as well um and and um I think
that
it really just depends on the specific
application layer code but I think it
will be helpful for exploiting these
vulnerabilities if you understand if
you're dealing with hidden property
abuse prototype poisoning or prototype
pollution right probably lots of people
have thought they had protop pollution
when they really had one of the former
and so then they weren't able to exploit
it or they weren't they weren't able to
structure it correctly and they gave up
on it and so maybe they need to return
to that to kind of figure out what they
missed there. Yeah, exactly. Um okay. Uh
so that that one's that one. I would
like to double click a little bit more
on that and the reason I was going to
kind of save it was I think that I'd
need to do a little bit more research on
it before I could do it full justice. So
I'll um I'll kind of circle back around
to that on a later week, but I I it's a
good idea to put it on the the listeners
radar for now. Um, all right. Last one
that I got, Joseph, here is I just put
in like I just put in the notes here.
Lack of hard-coded user confirmation for
sensitive uh agent action. And that is
how I phrased
a report that I submitted recently in
the AI world. And I'm wondering whether,
you know, and I can ask you about this
because you've had more experience in
the AI world um as far as vulnerability
assessments go. um is is this like
already a wellestablished bug type
because I feel like this is you know if
we were to do like an OASP top 10 for AI
I think this would be on it you know is
like there there is a aentic interface
that is has the ability to take actions
and one of those actions is get user
confirmation right and then in the
prompt the system prompt it's saying hey
before you do delete user user account
action. Make sure that you run action
get user consent, right? And it's
trusting the AI to do what you told it
to do there rather than integrating the
user consent flow into the delete user
account action so that the AI just calls
delete user account and it automatically
as from like a hard-coded perspective
gets user consent. Does that make sense?
Yep. Sorry, I didn't know if I was on
mute. Yeah. So, This is 10,000% a big
issue because it you're in like the
constant like it's the strongest tension
point I've seen between security and
convenience like and it's not just
convenience it's like people want fully
agentic employees fully agentic flows
like they want fully automated processes
and AI can give that to us but because
of the nature of security and the nature
of prompt injection being unsolved now
if you do run it in an unsupervised way,
which um the LLM I'm not a massive fan
of the LLM OAS top 10, but um there is
one on there called excessive agency and
I think that's probably uh what this
would fall under. Um I I would have to
do some thinking about whether I think
that your bug class is kind of like a
subtype of that or if it's or if they're
fully like overlap, right? Like if it's
always that same thing. But I but I do
agree with you. It's a it's a very
common vulnerability type, but it is
also and you know like I personally
still lean on the secure side. Like if
I'm running cursor, I don't run it in
yolo mode. I'm sure you don't either.
You don't want to break your laptop,
right? Right. Because you and so for
those of you that are listening that
don't know what yolo mode is, basically
anytime it's doing like a file read or a
file write or like it's running like a
command on the terminal like on the
command line, it will confirm with you.
You have to approve it. But that can be
annoying if it's going to run a bunch of
things. Sometimes it'll like list files
then move a file then rename a file and
you're like clicking approve approve
approve and so I think that that
convenience trade-off a lot of people
are going to take it and they're going
to just run it in YOLO mode or they're
going to run you know chat GPT operator
or whatever you know the thing we're
hacking on for Google like they're going
to run it and just trust it and it can
take sensitive actions without user
confirmation and right now computer or
operator in chat GPT and also a similar
concept exists for the Google one they
have this built-in notion of like just
telling the AI I to like ask for
confirmation if it's sensitive and
that's just not going to cut it, man.
It's not going to work, man. It's always
going to make it uh exploitable, you
know, via via prompt injection. And I
think that as we are dealing with these
sort of this sort of fuzzy tech, this
LLM sort of environment where it's not
deterministic. I think that uh this is a
valid finding personal like you you need
to address this from an architectural
level before you screw yourself. by
adding an action and trying to you know
get force the thing to get get consent
via an optional consent action itself.
So yeah, there is there is one strong
level of security that most people have
probably seen in chat GPT and Claude,
especially for um Claude specifically
for the desktop client when it's calling
MCP servers, it always asks for your
permission to connect on that first run.
But I think there's either an option to
say like trust the rest of this like um
like trust the rest of this conversation
or to say like only trust this once. And
I'm sure that 99% of people hit trust
for this conversation. But then but then
if it encounters any kind of prompt
injection payload while going like in
the future like in the rest of that
conversation while it's hitting some
other external data source or whatever
then all of a sudden it becomes
vulnerable again. And so yeah it's it's
like just really hard to even know how
to handle this because like you're
saying like I think it should be a valid
bug but I think a lot of companies and
um AI engineers are going to be like
well how can I even protect against
this? It ruins our product if they have
to click approve every 30 seconds you
know. Yeah. So it's that that internal
trade-off of like business use case
versus security. Um, so it'll be
interesting to see where the industry
lies. Yeah. All right, man. Is that a
wrap? That's a wrap. Thanks, dude.
That's the pod. Peace, y'all.
And that's a wrap on this episode of
Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
watching to the end, y'all. If you want
more critical thinking content, uh, or
if you want to support the show, head
over to
ctbb.show/isord. You can hop in the
community. There's lots of great
highlevel hacking discussion happening
there on top of master classes,
hackalongs, exclusive content, and a
full-time hunters guild. If you're a
full-time hunter, it's a great time.
Trust me. All right, I'll see you there.